Phone: (+64) 210 255 0720

E-mail: alexandr.basan@gmail.com

Skype: alexandr.basan

Portfolio: alexbasan.proalab.com

Alexandr Basan

Personal Information

Birthday 15 December 1986

Marital status Married

Residence Auckland, New Zealand

Languages English – Upper-Intermediate, Ukrainian – native, Russian – native.

Career Objectives

Senior Web Developer / Developer / Project manager / CEO / CTO

Personal Profile

I am efficient and highly motivated person with 11+ years of work experience in the IT Industry. I have strong technical skills and excellent interpersonal skills. I like to be challenged because it gives me a chance to grow and improve my managerial and professional skills gained through previous experiences in the IT sector. I am eager to learn and I have a genuine interest in computer science and business.

Tasks and purposes

- Web development
- Web design
- SaaS systems development
- API development

- User interface design
- o Front end development
- Database development
- Project management

phone: (+64) 210 255 0720 Page 1 of 7

Technical Skills

Programming and scripting

languages

HTML, XHTML, CSS, XML, JSON, JavaScript, CoffeeScript, AngularJS,

jQuery, Ruby, Rails, Java

Design frameworksBootstrap, Metro UI, Foundation, Font Awesome

Other services and systems Amazon web services (EC2, S3), Heroku, Google Maps API, Facebook

API, Twitter API, Google+ API, Google Currency API, New Relic Server Monitoring, Microsoft MSDN, I18n, RSpec, Capybara, Factory girl,

Android SDK

Content Management Systems Rails, Drupal, Mambo / Joomla, Wordpress

Operational systems Windows Desktop (2000, XP, Vista, 7, 8), Windows Server 2003, DOS,

Mac OS X (Leopard, Mavericks, Yosemite), Linux (SUSE, Mint, Ubuntu),

Android, iOS

Other skills Development of SaaS Systems, skills in code management system -

GIT. Installation and usage of Apache, Passenger, SQL Server, MySQL, PostgreSQL. Knowledge of principles and operations of basic networking protocols: TCP/IP, SMTP, POP3, HTTP, FTP, SSL. Skills in

Google Analytics, Google Adwords.

Functional experience

Position	Duration
Project Manager	8 years
Web Developer	5+ years

Technology	Expertise Level	Years
HTML / CSS	Very Strong	8+ yrs
Javascript, jQuery	Experienced	6 yrs
Ruby, Rails	Very Strong	5+ yrs
PostgreSQL, MySQL	Some Experience	5+ yrs
Bootstrap, Metro UI	Very Strong	5+ yrs
Amazon web services (EC2, S3), Heroku, Apache	Experienced	3 yrs
Google Maps API, Facebook API, Twitter API, Google+ API	Experienced	3 yrs

phone: (+64) 210 255 0720 Page 2 of 7

Education

2001 – 2004 Mariupol Electromechanical College (METS), Mariupol, Ukraine.

Junior specialist of repair and maintenance of electromechanical

equipment of buildings and structures.

2007 – 2013 Kharkiv National University of Radio Electronics (NURE), Kharkiv,

Ukraine (http://nure.ua/en/).

Specialist of telecommunication systems.

Courses and certificates

Coursera profile • Web Application Architectures, University of New Mexico

Programming Languages, University of Washington

<u>Codecademy profile</u> Ruby, HTML/CSS and course Rails for Zombie at Code School.

Work experience

Dec 2012 - Jan 2015

Proalab, LLC. (www.proalab.com)



Proalab develops perfect sites and SaaS projects using Ruby On Rails. Proalab creates projects for startups, e-commerce, small business solutions and many others.

Position:

CEO

Duties:

Setting corporate strategy and goals, building strong management team, managing financial operations, marketing strategy, creating company's culture, dealing with human resources, compliance with safety regulations, sales, PR, etc.

Projects:

- o www.aluminiumrepairs.co.nz
- www.teleport-ds.com
- saas.teleport-ds.com
- o cba-appraiser.herokuapp.com
- o dentsaas.herokuapp.com
- o and 50 others Rails and Mobile projects

Tools and technologies

Ruby, Rails, Bootstrap, Metro UI CSS 2.0, JavaScript, Ajax, Jquery, AngularJS, BackboneJS, CoffeeScript, I18n, PostgreSQL, MySQL, Heroku, Amazon S3, Google Maps API v.3, Facebook API, Twitter API, Google API, Google Currency API, New Relic Server Monitoring, Node JS, Microsoft

phone: (+64) 210 255 0720 Page 3 of 7

Feb 2013 - Jan 2015

Teleport, LLC. (www.teleport-ds.com)



First Ukrainian startup in the sphere of goods delivery for online stores. Cloud-based online delivery service Teleport combines order flows from online stores with delivery services and fully automates the process of orders delivery to customers.

Position:

Creator/CEO

Duties:

- Drafting software requirements;
- Creating plans for development and revision of software;
- Development and test teams management;
- Development and testing processes control.

Tools and technologies:

Ruby, Rails, Bootstrap, JavaScript, Ajax, Jquery, CoffeeScript, I18n, PostgreSQL, Heroku, Amazon S3, Google Maps API v.3, Facebook API, Twitter API, Google API, Google Currency API, New Relic Server Monitoring, RSpec.

Jul 2012 - Dec 2014

Credit Brokerage Agency, LLC. (www.cba.com.ua)



Real estate appraisal company that has experience in the independent evaluation by the International Valuation Standards (IVS) and International Financial Reporting Standards (IFRS).

Position:

Head of Information Technologies Department

Duties:

- Control of IT division;
- Implementation of corporate SaaS system, giving ability to work with the banks;
- Participation in working groups on company's business automation, implementation of new hardware and software.

Apr 2010 - Jun 2012

Terra Bank, PJSC. (www.terrabank.ua)



The Bank provides innovative products and solutions for people in the area of lending and deposits.

Position:

Head of Control and Planning division of the Information Technologies Department

Duties:

- o Developers subdivision management.
- o Development of internal documentation for IT Department;
- Collaboration with suppliers on the purchase and delivery of hardware and software, control on the expenses rate;
- Creation of cost estimates for the development of Information Technology Department and cost of opening new bank affiliates throughout Ukraine;
- o Participation in work groups on banking automation,

Oct 2009 - Apr 2010

Ukrgasbank, PJSC. (www.ukrgasbank.com)



Bank has undergone a progressive transformation from a corporate lending institution focused on financing and servicing Ukraine's oil & gas sector to the bank with a high growth, low risk and diversified business model. Since 2009 a controlling stake of 87.72% of the Bank's equity belongs to the Ukraine Ministry of Finance.

Position:

Head of Service division of the Information Technologies Department

Duties:

- 0 IT management;
- Implementation of Help Desk system (Astrosoft) and control of Help Desk subdivision;
- Development of internal documentation for IT Department;
- Development of processes and mechanisms for the department work-flow maintenance;
- Control of contracts concluded between IT companies and the \circ
- Implementation of an automated document management system (CASE).

Jul 2009 - Oct 2009

Avesta Insurance, UC. (www.avesta-ic.com.ua)



Company specializes in mass types of insurance for small and medium-sized businesses, and provides solutions and services for insurance and risk management for commercial and corporate customers.

Position:

Head of Information Technologies Department

Duties:

- o Development of company's website Joomla **CMS** (www.avesta-ic.com.ua);
- o Installing and configuring server software (Apache, IIS, Windows 2003 Server, Active Directory, DHCP, IDS);
- Software and hardware maintenance.

Nov 2007 - Jun 2009

The State Mortgage Institution. (www.ipoteka.gov.ua)



💹 ДЕРЖАВНА ІПОТЕЧНА УСТАНОВА

The main goal of The State Mortgage Institution is refinancing mortgage lenders (banks and non-bank financial institutions that conduct activities to secured mortgage loans), promoting the development of the mortgage lending.

Position:

Department Deputy Director, Department of Information Technologies

Duties:

- Implementation of business automation based on 1C Enterprise 8.1 software.
- Development of company's website Joomla CMS (www.ipoteka.gov.ua);
- Development of company's internal CRM system on Drupal CMS;
- Development of SaaS system for refinancing processes automation using Microsoft SharePoint Services;
- Organization of seminars and meetings with partner banks; 0
- Organization department documentation on software and

phone: (+64) 210 255 0720

Page 5 of 7

Oct 2006 - Nov 2007

Omega Insurance, JSC. (www.omega.ua)



Omega Insurance, was founded in 1994 and is a universal insurance company. Nowadays Omega Insurance has an extensive regional network, which includes 50 regional offices throughout Ukraine.

Position:

Head of Information Technologies Department

Duties:

- Coordinating IT work of company's branches;
- Development of company's website on Joomla CMS (www.omega.ua);
- Development of company's internal CRM system on Drupal CMS;
- Organization department documentation on software and hardware maintenance and data protection.
- Installing and configuring server software on FreeBSD (Apache, server management system Webmin, IDS, VPN) and Windows 2003 Server (Active Directory).

Sep 2005 - Sep 2006

Misto Bank, LLC. (www.mistobank.com.ua)



Misto Bank - a modern universal bank offering a full range of qualitative banking services in the financial market of Ukraine. Bank is based on the principles of openness, respect and trust, is aimed at establishing partnerships with clients to meet their needs.

Position:

Software engineer

Duties:

- Configuration and support of ATM (Wincorp Nixdorf Protopas), POST-terminals:
- Configuration and support of bank CRM system ODB (SCROOGE);
- Installation and support of local (Windows XP) and server stations (Novell NetWare 5.1), network equipment maintenance;
- Installing and configuring client-bank systems;
- Support of additional software (Western Union, system of municipal payments, Contact financial service, MoneyGram financial service, etc.).

Referees

Dmitriy Sidelnik

(+64) 21 767 298

Proalab LLC, Partner

anarionfilm@gmail.com

Valeriy Shevchenko

+38 067 238 04 90

Credit Brokerage Agency, LLC, CEO

valery.shevchenko@cba.com.ua

Troy Dobbs

(+64) 098387715

Aluminium Repairs Limited, Owner

aluminiumrepairs@gmail.com

phone: (+64) 210 255 0720 email: alexandr.basan@gmail.com

Notes

This page was left intentionally blank.

phone: (+64) 210 255 0720 Page 7 of 7